Yang, Bo

Developer

3

+1-415-420-9693



https://yang-bo.com



pop.atry@gmail.com



pop_atry



yang_bo



955091



Atry

About me —

I am a developer who knows how to create application frameworks.

I founded a number of open-source projects for creating micro-services, neural networks, reactive GUIs, and DSLs, which are stared 3000+ times on GitHub.

My current interests include machine learning infrastructure and the application of functional programming languages to real-world problems.

Skills

Scala

Machine Learning

Software Design

Agile Project Management

Hack *5.5 Haxe *5.5 OpenCL *5
DevOps *5 ActionScript *4
C++ *4 Java *4 JavaScript *4
Rust *4 OCaml *4 Testing *3
C *3 Spark *3 Akka *3

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Open-source projects

2021-2022 HHVM C++/Rust/OCaml is Meta's virtual machine to run Hack. I ported the open source branch of HHVM to NixOS and created CI pipeline for building, testing, and packaging HHVM. since 2018 is a framework to extend Scala language features in libraries. I also ported this framework to Haskell as Control.Dsl. since 2016 DeepLearning.scala and Compute.scala Scala are libraries for creating complex neural networks. since 2015 Binding.scala Scala is a reactive templating language for creating web and desktop GUI. 2015-2016 Microbuilder Haxe / Scala / Java / JavaScript is a toolkit to build system across micro-services implemented in various languages communicating via RESTful JSON API.

since 2012 haxe-continuation

Haxe

provides async/await syntax for Haxe.

since 2010 protoc-gen-as3

ActionScript3

is a Protocol Buffers plugin for ActionScript 3.

since 2007 other 100+ of open-source projects

[Publications]

2017

2017 More than React
2009 Adobe Flex 3: Training from the Source translator

Talks

2017 Deeplearning.Scala——Thoughts and practices on open source deep learning framework
2017 Monadic Deep Learning Strange Loop

DeepLearning.scala 2.0: Statically Typed Neural Networks

2017 Neural Networks & Functional Programming ArchData Summit · Beijing 2016 More than Async QCon · Beijing

2015 Specific-domain extension in an universal language ECUG Con

Experience

2019–2022 Meta Platforms Inc Software Developer I built machine learning infrastructure to detect payment fraud and integrated it into a variety of products. Then I joined the Hack/HHVM OSS team, where I was in charge

of maintaining HHVM's open-source branch.

2015-2019 Thoughtworks Inc Senior Consultant / Lead Consultant I maintained a number of open-source projects sponsored by ThoughtWorks. I also took the role of Consultant or Tech Lead in various delivery teams for creating mobile and web applications, as well as data platforms.

2014 Shenzhen QiFun Network Corp., LTD Chief Programmer I led the Q-Force Team in developing a game engine along with its related tools, and two mobile games.

2011-2013 Shenzhen Putaoteng Network Technology Co., Ltd. Co-founder I led the start-up team in developing a 3D side-scrolling game engine VinyHome and a social game Nan Da Nu Pei.

2008-2011 NetEase, Inc. Chief Programmer

I participated in various product teams as a developer or the technical lead, including Zhan Guo Feng Yun (web game), Ka Pai Dui Jue (web game), Deepcold (3D game engine).

2007 Beijing HiPiHi Information Technology Corp.,Ltd Software Engineer I developed variant components of both client-side and server-side for a 3D virtual world, HiPiHi World.

2006-2007 Beijing AutoNavi Software Co., Ltd. Software Engineer As a developer, I developed some components for a 3D navigation software.

Education

2002-2006 Southwest University of Political Science and Law Bachelor Of Laws